Continuing Studies fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Credit Programs, 1974 - 1998; F-94-3; 2.37 m of textual records
  - Distance Education Program, 1974 - 1992; F-94-3-1; 56 cm of textual records
    - Directed Independent Study Courses (DISC / DIS), 1974 - 1985; F-94-3-1-2; 6 cm of textual records
      - DISC correspondence - Chemistry, 1977 - 1980; F-94-3-1-2-6 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - DISC correspondence - Sociology / Anthropology, 1977 - 1981; F-94-3-1-2-7 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - DISC correspondence - Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies, 1978 - 1980; F-94-3-1-2-8 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - DISC correspondence - Kinesiology, 1978 - 1984; F-94-3-1-2-9 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - DISC correspondence - Education, 1978 - 1984; F-94-3-1-2-10 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - DISC correspondence - Mathematics, 1980 - 1985; F-94-3-1-2-11 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
    - Knowledge Network, 1982 - 1992; F-94-3-1-3; 4 cm of textual records
      Knowledge Network
      - SFU/Knowledge Network videotapes catalogue, 1982 - 1983; F-94-3-1-3-1 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - Program guides and telecourses, 1982 - 1983; F-94-3-1-3-2 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - SFU/Knowledge Network videotapes bibliography, 1983; F-94-3-1-3-3 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - Program guides and telecourses, 1984 - 1986; F-94-3-1-3-4 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - Knowledge Network Projects Consultative Committee, 1986; F-94-3-1-3-5 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - Oversized telecourse posters, 1987 - 1992; F-94-3-1-3-6
      - Knowledge Network II Project, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-1-3-7 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - Program guides and telecourses, 1989 - 1991; F-94-3-1-3-8 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
    - South Pacific Nutrition Project, 1985 - 1992; F-94-3-1-4; 20 cm of textual records
      - Correspondence and working papers, 1985 - 1987; F-94-3-1-4-1 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - Budget and working papers, 1987 - 1989; F-94-3-1-4-2 (Archival box - standard 94-15)
      - Funding correspondence, 1987 - 1992; F-94-3-1-4-3 (Archival box - standard 94-16)
      - Correspondence and working papers, vol. 1, 1988 - 1990; F-94-3-1-4-4 (Archival box - standard 94-16)
      - Correspondence and working papers, vol. 2, 1988 - 1990; F-94-3-1-4-5 (Archival box - standard 94-16)
      - Correspondence and working papers, vol. 3, 1988 - 1990; F-94-3-1-4-6 (Archival box - standard 94-16)
      - Meeting minutes and site reports, 1989; F-94-3-1-4-7 (Archival box - standard 94-16)
      - Project narrative report, 1990; F-94-3-1-4-8 (Archival box - standard 94-16)
      - Project summaries and background reports, 1990; F-94-3-1-4-9 (Archival box - standard 94-17)
      - Correspondence and working papers, 1990 - 1992; F-94-3-1-4-10 (Archival box - standard 94-17)
      - Project narrative report (final), 1991; F-94-3-1-4-11 (Archival box - standard 94-17)
  - Downtown Campus Program, 1978 - 1990; F-94-3-2; 25 cm of textual records 1 artifact
    SFU's Downtown Campus Program had a modest beginning on February 22, 1980 with a small storefront location and a couple of rented classrooms at 822 Howe Street. Developed as an extension of the Burnaby campus evening programs, the downtown program was established to help SFU strengthen its community identity and recruit new students. A selection of extension credit courses and non-credit community education programs were offered to adult students who sought to complete or upgrade their existing university education. By 1981 growing enrollment numbers forced the program to move to a larger site at 849 Howe Street. Known as the Downtown Education Centre (DEC), the space was shared with BCIT who managed and coordinated the Centre through their Division of Continuing Education and Industry Services.
    Faculty from the Burnaby campus traveled downtown to teach at the Centre and brought in community professionals to assist them. In 1983 the Downtown Campus Planning Committee was struck by Senate to survey the downtown community and assist in the planning of proposed sites for a downtown campus. Downtown enrollment continued to grow and each year new programs were tested as administrators worked towards developing a curriculum that would be unique to a downtown campus. During this time a number of programs were created including the School for Liberal and Professional Studies, the City Program, the Fine Arts Program, the Writing Program and the Professional Management Studies Program.
    In 1989 the new downtown campus was opened in the remodeled historic Spencer Building on West Hastings Street. Since then, SFU at Harbour Centre has continued to expand its curriculum to the needs of the downtown community, offering courses in sciences, liberal arts, and applied, professional and interdisciplinary fields of study leading to certificates, diplomas, and undergraduate and graduate degrees. In addition, SFU at Harbour Centre hosts professional development seminars, short courses, conferences and lectures.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the planning, development, and administration of the Downtown Campus Program and its successor, SFU at Harbour Centre. Activities, events and topics documented include downtown program proposals, budget development, student information packages, an invitation to the opening of the Downtown Program in 1980, student questionnaires, course schedules, Downtown Planning Committee meetings, and an engraved paperweight from SFU Harbour Center. Records include correspondence and working papers, minutes, statistics, reports, news releases, and financial working papers.
    For related records in this fonds see Series 1 (Dean's correspondence) for the Downtown Education Centre (F-94-1-0-0-15) and (F-94-1-0-0-23) for SFU Harbour Centre.
    - Downtown program, vol. 1, 1978 - 1980; F-94-3-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 94-17)
    - Downtown program, vol. 2, 1978 - 1980; F-94-3-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 94-17)
    - Correspondence and working papers, 1978 - 1990; F-94-3-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 94-17)
    - Space, 1979 - 1987; F-94-3-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 94-18)
    - Correspondence and working papers, 1980 - 1984; F-94-3-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 94-18)
    - Statistics, vol. 1, 1980 - 1985; F-94-3-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 94-18)
    - Statistics, vol. 2, 1980 - 1985; F-94-3-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 94-18)
    - Downtown program, vol. 1, 1981 - 1985; F-94-3-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 94-18)
    - Downtown program, vol. 2, 1981 - 1985; F-94-3-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 94-18)
    - Downtown Council, 1981 - 1985; F-94-3-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 94-18)
    - Planning Committee correspondence, minutes and working papers, vol. 1, 1981 - 1986; F-94-3-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
    - Planning Committee correspondence, minutes and working papers, vol. 2, 1981 - 1986; F-94-3-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
    - Capital campaign strategy, 1983 - 1987; F-94-3-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
    - Sites, 1984; F-94-3-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
  - Extension Credit Program, 1974 - 1990; F-94-3-3; 5 cm of textual records
    The Extension Credit Program began in 1973 as a result of a Senate motion delegating all responsibility for off-campus programs to Continuing Studies. The program provided educational opportunities for persons who could not attend day classes, but through evening, Intersession, or Summer Session courses could complete a degree, upgrade existing education or enhance personal academic interests. Professional programs were also offered to teachers through evening and summer classes. The opening of the downtown campus at Harbour Centre in 1989 enhanced the visibility of the Extension Credit Program as it offered courses aimed towards the advanced recurring educational needs of the business, professional and cultural communities in Vancouver's urban core. The Extension Credit Program remains active as of 2005 and allows students to obtain graduate degrees, post baccalaureate diplomas, and selected undergraduate certificates on a part time basis by day or evening study.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the administration and development of the Extension Credit Program. Activities, events and topics documented include guidelines for developing an off-campus program, planning for courses offered at Britannia Community Centre, annual program reports, student questionnaires, policies and procedures development, and reports by the Senate Committee on Continuing Studies. Records include agendas and minutes, correspondence, working papers, statistics, reports, and course proposals.
    - General correspondence, 1974 - 1988; F-94-3-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
    - Special audit, 1975 - 1979; F-94-3-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
    - Correspondence, reports and working papers, 1975 - 1990; F-94-3-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
  - Gerontology Program, 1980 - 1982; F-94-3-4; 5 cm of textual records
    The Gerontology Program was developed in 1982 with the establishment of the SSHRC funded Gerontolgy Research Centre (GRC). That same year the post-baccalaureate diploma in Gerontology was introduced and in 1983 the Department of Gerontology was formed to serve as the focal point for research, education and information on individual and population aging. Courses offered through the program address aging and the built environment, health promotion, and population health and aging. Students are trained in the critical analysis of the health care system and in the planning, design, research, and evaluation of working, living, and recreational environments for older persons. As of 2005, the program also offers a minor, masters and Ph.D. degree in Gerontology.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the development, funding and administration of the Gerontology program. Activities, events and topics documented include history of the program, proposal for a post-baccalaureate Diploma in Gerontology, liaison with the Universities Council of British Columbia, workshop planning and conference proposals, SSHRC funding, and the opening of the Gerontology Centre in 1982. Records include correspondence, minutes, reports, contracts, course proposals, draft budgets and working papers.
    - Correspondence, reports and working papers, vol. 1, 1980 - 1982; F-94-3-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 94-19)
    - Correspondence, reports and working papers, vol. 2, 1980 - 1982; F-94-3-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
    - Correspondence, reports and working papers, vol. 3, 1980 - 1982; F-94-3-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
  - Interior and Non-Metropolitan Programs, 1975 - 1989; F-94-3-5; 40 cm of textual records
    The Interior and Non-Metropolitan program began in 1975 as a response to government concern that residents in interior regions of BC were excluded from university education. After a year of offering credit courses at non-metropolitan colleges, SFU began to formally develop a distance education program and initiated a three-year experimental program in Kelowna offering degree completion programs in Psychology and Biological Sciences. SFU's goal was to design a distance education program that would provide an opportunity for all persons in BC to complete a degree without the usual attendance at UBC, UVic or SFU. By this time UBC and UVic were also offering interior programs and together with SFU ensured that the courses offered by each institution did not overlap each other. SFU interior courses were developed by university faculty and delivered with the assistance of the Office of Continuing Studies. Under the jurisdiction of the Ministry of Education, the Interior University Programs Board approved courses and provided program funding from the provincial government.
    In 1978 the the Interior Universities Programs Board was disbanded and replaced by the Open Learning Institute. The Open Learning Institute took responsibility for offering a bachelor of Arts and Science Program in cooperation with colleges, while universities remained responsible for offering professional programs. Throughout the late 1970s and early 1980s SFU initiated a number of programs that were delivered out of university centres in Kamloops, Kelowna, Prince George and Fort St. John. The Faculty of Education offered a variety of credit and non-credit programs and other departments developed courses in response to school district requests. Courses were taught through a combination of face-to-face instruction, directed independent study courses and via Knowledge Network telecourse programming.
    In 1984, the provincial government established the University Consortium to increase access to post-secondary distance education courses. The Open Learning Agency (formerly the Open Learning Institute) was selected to be the central administrative headquarters for the University Consortium. SFU, UBC and UVic were integrated into the new program as consortium partners, delivering courses and programs in cooperation with various educational institutions, professional associations, workplaces, and community organizations. As of 2005 SFU's relationship with the Open Learning Agency remains in place. Through the British Columbia Open University (BCOU), a division of the Open Learning Agency, students can register and take distance education courses delivered by SFU without having to be admitted to the university.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the development and administration of the Interior and Non-Metropolitan Programs offered by SFU. Activities, events and topics documented include program development, the Interior University Program Board, SFU's Planning Committee on Interior Programming, administration of the Kelowna and Fraser Valley programs and budget planning. Records include agendas and minutes, program and course proposals, budget and financial working papers, correspondence, reports and working papers.
    For records relating to the Interior Program Planning Committee dated 1977-1979 see Office of the Vice President, Finance and Administration (F-28-7-16). For further correspondence and reports on the Interior program dated 1976-1978 see Office of the Vice President, Academic (F-29-8-0-0-17 to F-29-8-0-0-19).
    - Kelowna Program, 1975 - 1982; F-94-3-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
    - Report of the Planning Committee on Interior Programming, 1977; F-94-3-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
    - Draft proposals for interior programs, 1977; F-94-3-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
    - Interior Program - correspondence, minutes and working papers, 1977 - 1980; F-94-3-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
    - Fraser Valley Program, 1977 - 1981; F-94-3-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
    - Interior Program - SFU/UBC/UVic, vol. 1, 1978 - 1980; F-94-3-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 94-20)
    - Interior Program - SFU/UBC/UVic, vol. 2, 1978 - 1980; F-94-3-5-0-7 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Interior Program - SFU/UBC/UVic, vol. 3, 1978 - 1980; F-94-3-5-0-8 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Interior Program - SFU/UBC/UVic, vol. 4, 1978 - 1980; F-94-3-5-0-9 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Interior Program - budget, vol. 1, 1978 - 1983; F-94-3-5-0-10 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Interior Program - budget, vol. 2, 1978 - 1983; F-94-3-5-0-11 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Interior program proposals and budget requests, 1979; F-94-3-5-0-12 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Interior 1980-1981 program proposals, 1979; F-94-3-5-0-13 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Report on University Programs in the Non-Metropolitan Areas of BC, [198-?]; F-94-3-5-0-14 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Non-metropolitan 1981-1982 program proposals, 1980; F-94-3-5-0-15 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Interior Program - correspondence and working papers, 1980 - 1989; F-94-3-5-0-16 (Archival box - standard 94-21)
    - Non-metropolitan 1982-1983 program proposals, 1981; F-94-3-5-0-17 (Archival box - standard 94-22)
    - Interior Program - 1982/1983 budget submission, 1981; F-94-3-5-0-18 (Archival box - standard 94-22)
    - Interior Program - SFU/UBC/UVic, vol. 1, 1981 - 1982; F-94-3-5-0-19 (Archival box - standard 94-22)
    - Interior Program - SFU/UBC/UVic, vol. 2, 1981 - 1982; F-94-3-5-0-20 (Archival box - standard 94-22)
    - Interior Program - W. Uegama working papers, 1981 - 1982; F-94-3-5-0-21 (Archival box - standard 94-22)
    - Interior Program correspondence, 1981 - 1983; F-94-3-5-0-22 (Archival box - standard 94-22)
    - Interior Program - 1983/1984 budget submission, 1982; F-94-3-5-0-23 (Archival box - standard 94-22)
    - Non-metropolitan 1983-1984 program proposals, 1982; F-94-3-5-0-24 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
    - Interior Program - correspondence and working papers, 1982 - 1984; F-94-3-5-0-25 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
    - Interior Program - 1984/1985 budget submission, 1983; F-94-3-5-0-26 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
    - Non-metropolitan 1984-1985 programs, 1983; F-94-3-5-0-27 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
    - Non-metropolitan 1985-1986 programs, 1984; F-94-3-5-0-28 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
  - Prison Education Program, 1980 - 1993; F-94-3-6; 94 cm of textual records
    SFU launched the Prison Education Program (PEP) on April 1, 1984 after negotiating a three-year contract with the Federal Government to deliver a university program for male inmates at four penitentiaries - Kent, Mountain Head, Matsqui, and William Head/Metchosin. Assuming responsibility from the University of Victoria who had run the program for twelve years, PEP staff worked quickly to ensure a smooth administrative transition of the program and re-registration of the inmates as SFU students. The new program was assigned a dual home at SFU where all academic affairs of the program were administered through the Office of the Dean of Arts and a Steering Committee, and all administrative affairs of the program - including appointment of its Director, Stephen Duguid and its Program Coordinator, Henry Hoekema - were run under the guise of the Office of Continuing Studies.
    Teaching staff for Kent, Mountain Head and Matsqui institutions were recruited from SFU while faculty at William Head were drawn extensively from UVic. In the course of its duration, the Prison Education Program established a library program at each institution, administered GED (grade 12 equivalency) courses, and offered courses in the Liberal Arts leading to certificate, diploma and degree completion. The program also sponsored courses and workshops in Writing and the Fine and Performing Arts and had a transition program for paroled inmates who chose to complete their education at SFU's Burnaby campus. After a few short years, the program grew to be very successful, garnering support from other SFU departments, developing a network of contacts in the field of prison education, initiating a series of seminars and Occasional Papers, and regularly publishing the Prison Journal. Despite the program being cancelled in the early 1990's due to government cutbacks, SFU continues today to be recognized as a leader in the field of prison education.
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the administration and development of the Prison Education Program. Activities, events and topics documented include liaison with the federal government and SFU departments, library proposals, course scheduling, Library Technician meetings, recognition and awards ceremonies, the SFU Prison Education Newsletter, and copies of the serial Prison Journal. Records include agendas and minutes, annual reports, correspondence, working papers, contracts, course proposals and outlines, reports, statistics, budgets and financial reports, reference materials, and publications.
    No further accruals to the sub-series are expected as the Prison Education Program is no longer active. However, a number of missing records were identified by the Archivist during processing and may be acquired at a future date.
    - Administration, 1980 - 1993; F-94-3-6-1; 29 cm of textual records
      - Prison Education Program pamphlet, [198-?]; F-94-3-6-1-1 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
      - Prison Journal, no. 1-3, 1981 - 1983; F-94-3-6-1-2 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
      - Occasional Papers on Prison Education, 1984; F-94-3-6-1-3 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
      - SFU Prison Education Program contract - correspondence, 1984 - 1985; F-94-3-6-1-4 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
      - Prison Journal, no. 4-5, 1984 - 1985; F-94-3-6-1-5 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
      - General correspondence, 1984 - 1986; F-94-3-6-1-6 (Archival box - standard 94-23)
        Restricted in part
      - Prison Education Program annual reports, 1984 - 1986; F-94-3-6-1-7 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - Matsqui Institution - Correctional Service of Canada, 1984 - 1988; F-94-3-6-1-8 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - Policies and correspondence, 1984 - 1988; F-94-3-6-1-9 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - PEP correspondence with SFU departments, 1984 - 1988; F-94-3-6-1-10 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - Ferndale Institution - Correctional Service of Canada, 1984 - 1989; F-94-3-6-1-11 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
        Restricted in whole
      - Prison Education Program working papers, vol. 1, 1984 - 1993; F-94-3-6-1-12 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - Prison Education Program working papers, vol. 2, 1984 - 1993; F-94-3-6-1-13 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - University Education in Prison: A Documentary Record of the Experience in BC 1974-1985, F-94-3-6-1-14 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - Sessional instructors, 1986 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-15 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - Certificate Program in Literacy Instruction, 1987 - 1988; F-94-3-6-1-16 (Archival box - standard 94-24)
      - Prison Journal, no. 6-8, 1987 - 1989; F-94-3-6-1-17 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - SFU Senate correspondence, 1987 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-18 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Mountain - recognition and awards ceremony, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-6-1-19 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - New student services, 1988 - 1989; F-94-3-6-1-20 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Certificate in Liberal Arts, 1988 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-21 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Ferndale - correspondence, 1989; F-94-3-6-1-22 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Matsqui - correspondence, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-23 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Prison advising, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-24 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Matsqui - recognition and awards ceremony, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-25 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Sessional Handbook, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-26 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - SFU Prison Education Program Newsletter, 1989 - 1990; F-94-3-6-1-27 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Kent - recognition and awards ceremony, 1990; F-94-3-6-1-28 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Prison Education Program Steering Committee, 1992; F-94-3-6-1-29 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Ceremonies, 1992; F-94-3-6-1-30 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Prison Education Program problems and budgets, 1992 - 1993; F-94-3-6-1-31 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
      - Prison Education Program budget, 1992 - 1993; F-94-3-6-1-32 (Archival box - standard 94-25)
        Open with enclosures